Colton Kaiser

Denver, CO | kaiserc2@seattleu.edu | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/coltonkaiser

Portfolio: coltonkaiser.dev | GitHub: github.com/ckaiser258

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Passionate software engineer with 3 years of experience. My experience provides me with a diverse knowledge of technologies, strong analytical skills, communication skills, and a systems-driven mindset which informs my coding. I combine my leadership skills with my software engineering expertise to contribute to organizations that value professionalism, collaboration, and offer a rich environment for constant growth and improvement.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

ReactJS, Next.js, Typescript, JavaScript, GraphQL, Apollo, Prisma, Node.js, PostgreSQL, Cypress, Material UI, HTML/CSS, Git Version Control, Agile Development, Front End Development, Full Stack Development, CI/CD

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer II Denver, CO / Remote

Promoboxx

11/2022 - Current

- Creating and improving large features for the application across multiple projects still utilizing JavaScript, React,
 Typescript, GraphQL/Apollo, Material UI, Formik, and other technologies. Using agile development and CI/CD across multiple environments.
- In addition to coding and coordinating with other engineers across multiple teams, regularly coordinating with the Product team to decide on the best decisions to make for features and consult on the best ways to execute them.
- Squad leader for multiple projects, including Instagram Automation, which has resulted in an over 10X increase in Instagram shares across users of the application.
- Currently squad leader for a "Sub Brands" project which will result in a more accurate view of the app's value, effectiveness, and profitability for investors. Resulting in more cash flow for the company and buy-in from investors.

Software Engineer IPromoboxx

Denver, CO / Remote
11/2020 – 11/2022

- Worked in a fast-paced startup environment utilizing JavaScript, React, Typescript, GraphQL/Apollo, Material UI, Formik, and other technologies.
- Developed and improved features within the application and solved bugs.
- Tested and deployed code across differing environments.
- Coordinated with frontend, backend, and data teams to solve and predict issues, and come to solutions when needed.
- Used CircleCI for CI/CD across multiple environments.
- Used Jira for agile development, ticket management, feature/bug pointing, and task delegation.

Volunteer Software Engineer

Seattle, WA 08/2020 – 11/2020

Snowpool

- Assisted a team from Veda Environmental in the development of a carpooling application aimed at making Washington's snow sport destinations more accessible and environmentally approachable for the residents of the local areas.
- Worked with a team of software engineers, requiring effective git version control, communication, teamwork, meeting deadlines, and setting/adhering to clear expectations.
- Utilized React, React Native, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, and PostgreSQL to develop features.
- Worked with UX/UI designers to implement mockups/wireframes to create an engaging user experience.

Software Engineering Fellowship

Seattle, WA 04/2020 - 08/2020

Flatiron School

• Developed skillsets in Ruby, Rails, Javascript, React/Redux, SQL, Computer Science fundamentals, HTML/CSS, data structure libraries for solving algorithms, and created multiple projects/full-stack applications.

• Learned full-stack software engineering via test-driven development, using git version control to collaborate on pair programming projects, and solo projects.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Al Powered Travel and Language Learning App (In Development) - Github

An AI powered application that allows users to generate personalized exercises to learn any language in the world, generate words and phrases they should be aware of in any location on earth, ask any travel-related question they want to a chatbot, and translate any language into any other language they'd like.

- Built using Next.js, React, Typescript, and the OpenAl API
- Backend built with GraphQL/Apollo, Prisma, Node.js, and PostgreSQL
- Utilizes GraphQL Codegen for increased type safety, improved developer experience, and consistency
- Utilizes NextAuth for user authentication/authorization

Performance Mapper - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo Video

An athletic performance monitoring tool that allows strength and conditioning coaches to monitor the performance and injury trends of their teams/athletes

- Used React, React Bootstrap, and Material UI for the frontend user experience
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side
- Created a Rails backend with BCrypt to allow users to securely store, access, and modify their information
- Used React ChartJS to display recorded subjective data for individual athletes as well as objective trends in performance and injuries throughout the user's teams

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Full Stack Software Development, Software Engineering Immersive Program	Seattle, WA 08/ 2020
Seattle University (3.7 GPA) M.A. in Sports Administration & Leadership	Seattle, WA 06/ 2019
Arizona State University B.S. in Exercise Science	Phoenix, AZ 06/ 2016